oh all right Thank You Raymond for
joining me and just so people know who
I'm talking to people we have our names
down in the corner we're on we're not on
camera because our internet is a little
laggy although it looks like just turn
ours on so you can see us at least
briefly and then if we have trouble
weekend yeah does it quite doesn't quite
work out for boy so we want to be able
to hear each other's it's normally a
time my kids still sleeping for it but I
got her to go to bed a little how many
look yeah
just one you think it was eight but it's
just like how old is she she's seven and
stuck inside is obviously being
seven-year-old yes as they should be at
7:00 and ago I don't know it it's
already in the same time zone yeah yeah
we're Pacific all right this time I'm in
Arizona so alright but uh we are we're
not being affected by the inside I think
because you know we're out in the middle
of nowhere so quite frankly we're
allowed to go outside oh right okay
guide you I go over to the golf course a
couple times
well yeah so I was gonna share a little
bit about my personal journey and maybe
hear yours a little bit more I I started
programming in 1980 when I was six or
seven and you know stayed with that and
got higher up
Highschool as a program residents as a
software engineer so I kind of had the
career for Game one and you know when I
started looking at systems analysis
shortly after I learned to read and
write you know I started looking around
I just always thought that people must
be really dumb because these systems are
all designed so badly I mean everything
is just everything to me was stupid no
and you know so this is my world view
entering entering the workforce and
entering the world and I was an only
child and spent a lot of time on the
computer and a lot of time kind of
outdoors playing and stuff and getting
in trouble and trying everything there
was to try in the world and not really
doing doing good in school because
school was stupid too because well it
just didn't seem it just did not
resonate with the way things ought to be
it was just all like I don't even know
how to describe how or what I thought
but anyway I I entered the workforce and
was a professions 400 and building
marketing krypton I've been doing all
the PC support for he worked occasion
for three locations and building out the
Novell Network and running cat5 cable
and coax in those days through the drop
ceiling and putting wire ends on and
configuring the servers and I was you
know I was everybody's go-to guy and his
medium company it was a great you know
career thing I had gone there if I
wanted a career but I didn't like the
time schedules I didn't like working in
a cubicle
I didn't started getting more
entrepreneurial and ended opening a
computing up opening computer store in
the last few years that you could even
conceivably do that custom-built
computers and things like that got into
you know business support and business
networking and then of course the
internet came around didn't we started
doing internet services around 98 went
back to the people
wanting to pay for websites and anyway I
did that for a few years
did good I have a couple different
businesses that a web design firm down
in Florida different things but I always
did good at raising the money and and
starting something off and getting
picking sales volumes we did 50,000 a
month some months at this computer store
and web sites and 60 days it at the
operation down in Florida and but I
couldn't at all - actually we manage and
run a business right and uh um so
eventually I kind of moved out to New
Mexico in the middle of nowhere bought
some property and just said I'm I'm
getting the world behind and just gonna
do my house out here this be away from
off completely
yeah I can try to edit this part out we
posted up whoo editing practice
okay okay is this any better yeah okay I
switched over to varieties and now I
don't know whether anything I said is
getting through or not I was just kinda
talking and talking some of it was
getting through I was getting about 90%
of it which honestly is my normal
because of my my deafness so we're doing
Oh interesting yet so where did I cut
off you were talking about your tech and
and the computer company I don't know
exactly exactly where it cut off but it
was in that that realm of you coming
into where you where you are now your
computer journey okay yeah I had a
couple different working businesses and
that was always it was easy to get them
started and get them going and get
decent amount of sales coming in but
actually maintaining human relationships
and building a company was not my thing
because you know I there's only child
who you know became this weird
antisocial person because I just wasn't
impressed with society and spent a lot
of time on the computers and there was
none like me at that time you know
there's lots of these kids nowadays we
have each other at least it could be hit
I searched at least be antisocial
socially you know but so anyway it was
just a very interesting version of the
world but did well pop and career when I
couldn't maintain them eventually moved
out to New Mexico where I thought I
could be just get away from people more
and and I just you know had to find a
way to make money there and found the
very easiest way to turn on a system and
have money just roll into my bank
account which was multilevel marketing
software development so I helped people
launch these multi-level marketing
companies that turned out to be very
lucrative and what it's a it's a game a
win right the easiest possible way to
just siphon in money from all the flows
and just have it come into my bank
account and so I got to be powerful in
the world and experience what that was
like with money and realized that that
wasn't actually the answer to happiness
or anything it's worse at this time
and I met a woman and we when the money
started running out she ran out but I
think the day we signed her divorce
papers we probably also conceived their
first daughter so it's kind of how that
way to more over the span of about ten
years so I have three daughters now and
as I was moving into this but nothing
was permanent with her and as I was
moving into fatherhood in these things
and as the relationship was falling
apart I'm realizing money's not the
answer and I'm realizing things are not
what I thought I had the world figured
out and apparently I know right right
about that time Ron Paul was running for
president in 2007 and he was talking
about the money system in the Federal
Reserve and how we can do everything we
want with you know electing different
politicians to office but if you don't
actually look at the underlying power
structure that fuels this whole machine
and so I went down the rabbit hole you
know and ended up starting a radio
station online radio station and
organizing a March and about 10,000
people showed up in Washington DC and we
marched from Washington Monument down to
the Capitol lawn where we rallied all
day and had a great time Ron Paul spoke
and Amy wolf spoke and so another win
felt like a huge win this is we're gonna
change the world the revolution has
begun no is just a drop in the bucket
nobody actually cared that end dozen
people showed up in DC it's like another
eye-opening discovery process so I
started going more internal around
2009-10 let go some of the anger realize
that changing the world happens by
changing myself eventually over the
years doing some more transformational
work being taking full responsibility
for everything in my reality including
all the things that was angry about
recognizing the oneness of all things
recognizing the things I'm angry about
and other people are just the shadow
parts of myself and all that kind of
work and really getting into what it
takes to be an intentional community and
what it takes that actually get along to
do work together in the world started
really taking an analytical look so I'm
learning in other words I'm learning to
be social from a very engineering
standpoint
you could say learning to be human right
you know capital might own emotionals
and emotions and feel of people's
emotions and actually relate and things
like this and so you know as you as we
speak today I'm 15 years into even
beginning this so I'm like I'm like a 15
year old and it's social sense in a lot
of ways and like so that's you know the
interesting part is that you know I'm
proposing solutions for people but I'm
not actually like a people person but
you know it like but I want to be and it
feels good to be it's just I'm really
really behind most people's development
and understanding complex social
patterns but as I do learn a my day I
write write about them and I look I put
them you know I identify the power
especially the power and money struggles
that people have and how we can avoid
those things that's really what spurred
me on to all this work so eventually I
Furion came along in 2016 I started
playing with that and I really was
excited that this could be the answer
I've been looking for you know and
started right is lodging some smart
contracts and noticed that we had the
scalability issues right away it took me
like a month to actually get a full node
running to download the whole etherion
blockchain because not only do you have
to download the whole ledger you also
have to execute every smart contract
transaction that happened since the
inception of the blockchain so it's a
really slow process to run a full node
and that was four years ago I can't even
imagine what it is now and so and then
the coding language solidity was just
kind of clunky and old-fashioned and it
just you know just not I knew this was
not the way and so looked around and
found holo chain and I said this this I
can build on this this is what I need
whatever these guys are talking about
and I mean no yet so I got on a call
with art-rock and some other people and
they ultimately invited me to come to
their summer house program running in
San Francisco I had my kids I had them
half a year six months on six months off
so I my final six months I was actually
living we were living in the desert near
Palm Springs mostly outdoors and
[Music]
money I had been on a subconscious about
poverty for about ten years apparently
and I didn't know like I was angry about
everything and didn't want money and
didn't wanna be part of any of it
anybody I had three daughters to raise
and I was finding community and but
anyhow I just came the state came that
we were we were living that way and I
realized I had everything I need I kind
of came to peace for the first time with
money like where I wasn't trying to get
lots of it and I wasn't angry about the
whole system and just kind of was in a
new state of release and they went back
with their mom shortly thereafter I
joined the whole attain team they
ultimately invited me to join the core
dev team and go with them to Europe to
launch the ICL they needed kind of a
hack squad of people that were just
willing to throw everything into this
project and I certainly in that and was
super honored to have that opportunity
and yeah within six months of that
moment of peace with money um you know I
could be ICL when I looked at my net
worth on papers is amazing how quickly
like just the release of knack on that
story where as soon as you release and
you fully be exist in a state of
abundance how the universe answers with
that and and so that's really part of
the drive is that I want everybody to
experience that I want everybody to find
their joy and what they do find
something they're passionate about
something they're good doing and just do
it and then have the University thank
you for that offering and feel and the
abundance to flow so that's really the
key to what what I'm what's motivating
me at a core factor of leaving this
opportunity because I certainly you know
dance this line if I don't want more for
myself than anybody else has and yet I
recognize the need for people people to
have a a game field of playing on which
the more they can help other people the
more they can win the game right so it's
like you know equality doesn't work but
equal opportunity does kind of thing
right and if we can create equal
opportunity percent everybody to find
their passion their joy and contribute
to the world in the way then everybody
should have opportunity to the more you
can help other people the more you win
the game and so
yeah that leads me to a pasta men
retreat I did over the over the new
decade over Chrisman days of entering
the new decade where was just a whole
new level of transformation for me and
personally knowing when you up a piece
that I had never ever experienced before
nothing remotely like it and being
actually held in loving kindness was
that something familiar in my life
didn't happen in a young age didn't
really ever happen because of that and
anyway so so yeah it's like you know I
can only dirty out loud is part of what
I'm offering to the world and that's
just fine with me
is it very but as a very personal you
know very deeply personal thing that I'm
moving through interpersonally and and
feel like the species is moving through
as well and I'm just you know one little
chart of the out of the mirror that we
all hope to each other and so here we
are I wrote that article and then named
my work protocol that love because
ultimately you know you got yes from the
article that there's this kind of
dichotomy between loving control is
really the fundamental pattern that I've
been I've been fighting against control
and in doing so trying to control my
reality
so really fighting against those who
would want to have control that's my own
version of trying to have control and so
anyway it's some weird dichotomy in
there but some weird some weird way of
letting wall paradox some weird paradox
what that is but anyway so yeah it's
really exciting to meet you because
it seems like a lot of whatever however
you got there which I'd love to get more
about you'd like a very compatible
vision and alignment and no protocol not
love is a technical protocol at least in
terms of where I've put my work it's a
technical at the digital protocol
specification I've also done a lot of
work over the years and what's not as
much my specialty but which is super
important is the actual human
interaction of protocol part you know
really really bringing in perhaps more
more you know feminine energy around
that part of the work as we're team
building is exciting to me and yeah
that's the whole thing so it was great
to pop in the game be and see going on
and the level of conversation and and
then just kind of the the energy the
interaction you guys are having and the
transparency you choose to have is all
really really exciting thank you for all
that and thank you for holding space for
me to wander my way in there yeah
absolutely happy that you were able to
come Saturday right yeah there's a lot
that we have that's definitely in
alignment even listen to your story it's
funny the parallels that are both and
this paradox and dichotomy I'm like
that's basically my life like it's like
holding both sides of the spectrum
holding the paradox holding the
dichotomy and see because you can hold
both of the dichotomy everyone else is
one or the other and I'm like I'm either
end o both end
I mean your childhood talking about that
you could see systems and they couldn't
so they must be dumb I actually came to
the opposite conclusion
I could see systems and like how
ridiculous this is but I must not
understand it like I need morning for me
yeah yeah hasn't quite make sense and
then it didn't it took me into probably
my 30s uh-huh it was like gradual like
Christianity falling away was like oh my
parents and the clergy you don't
actually know what the they're
talking about and even then like getting
into science and logic and then like
actually science and logic doesn't know
what the markets about and and
getting there of like okay now I don't
have complied didn't and still don't
have complete confidence that I
everything I need to know and at the
same time like once because I got I had
to I first needed knowledge then I got
to the point where I couldn't put in new
information and I realized how
intelligent I was at the same time as
realizing how unintelligent the world is
like individuals are intelligent but
collectively it's like we give our power
up to governments they don't know what's
going on any more than my parents did
when I was kid like this visit and like
it doesn't actually matter how much I
know is I'm just gonna be more miserable
in my knowledge rather it's about like
how like there's even if I knew all of
human knowledge if the person I'm
talking to doesn't it's actually not
helpful like it's it just makes me it's
like do your research well what does
that mean what does that actually what
Ken so I came to a lot of my stuff and
then your technology background opposite
spare don't technology doesn't make
sense to me but I can see the potential
in the systems of Technology and I think
we're very much as human beings and
individuals our purpose on this planet
is a combination of what we're amazing
at that we don't even know how amazing
we're at it because it's a it's easy for
us and what is hard for us that's easy
for everyone else and so it's that
combination of like like you're here to
connect people but you have trouble with
people right I'm here to like actually
create technology that's usable when I
don't I only just got a discord
yesterday after Nick posted and gave me
it was like fine because I have so many
discord accounts and that's kind of the
broken pieces that it won't let you on
and I figured it out because I could get
into a complaining about discord but
that's felt important this conversation
was like okay I already died on my end
I'm here I'm in with my original account
we'll see we'll see if anything comes of
it right my story is very much going
through science
Ed's that's my actual background is in
science biology ecology genetics and
well I was in university I got diagnosed
with brain tumors which put me on a
completely different course of realizing
what science and health care can't give
you like they don't actually have
solutions they're not actually there to
heal you they don't even care about why
things happen and that
but as a science student looking to make
sense of the world and then having that
happen now with hindsight of life all
that was exactly was supposed to happen
and then my brain thinking I could cram
enough information I could solve the
world's problems I can no longer cram it
in now I'm very much a piece with
everything I need to know I already know
and what can I do from this point with
what I have working within my
limitations that's why before we started
the recording I talked about that video
I saw that someone had posted about like
begging for people to come and then I
just found game B and in there I'm like
like all I can do is have a conversation
you can't cheat but like I need the
other people to do the executive
function to do the other pieces and I'm
like to some degree nothing's changed in
the last eight months I don't have what
I was looking for that and at the same
time everything's changed I'm like look
at my screen show out of my Street yard
account I just tweeted of like here's
all the conversations I'm taking part in
this week right and yeah they're world
changing like it's like all I'm doing is
having conversations and in a large way
it's huge like I'm like actually I'm
doing a hell of a lot in my easy
capacity and and how I got here like
even when you're talking on MLMs I'm
obsessed with other lemons I actually
really like like the math of them like I
want to see I love sitting I'm never
gonna buy them but I used to can I'm
used to like I've started MLMs I've
started businesses I've never made a
dollar at any of them because of my
battle of poverty my subconscious now
now it's more of a conscious vow and I'm
like you know what I'm not I have a bit
of a problem here saying there at the
end about like your abundance finds you
in the self-help community that happens
that that wording right like if you're
doing it right you'll find health and
wealth and if you're doing it wrong in
whatever way it's going and it's not to
say what you said that's right into it
it goes the other way and for me I
haven't found health and I haven't found
wealth and I'm okay with it cuz I'm okay
not finding health and wealth until we
all find health and wealth and I still a
hundred percent less than what you're
saying not we don't need everyone to
take a vow of poverty that's not
actually what we need we need people
with resources to put them into Gabey
but I also fundamentally think that if
game a works for you you actually can't
quite conceptualize
very much until you have some kind of we
hit a wall somewhere in your life and it
may not be financial if you're well if
you're a good game a player and but but
then what happens is you can buy your
way out of it you hit a wall and then
your way through it all your all your
shadow and all your everything you have
to do the processes you can just make
your will happen in the world and in any
way yeah I didn't mean to cut you out
there at the same time like when I first
wasn't able to go back to work after my
maternity leave and had to go on like to
the food bank and do all of these things
that I wasn't wasn't not planning on
doing we're doing money kept finding me
like what I was seeking it when I was
doing the MLM I got in such debt because
there was this idea that in the future I
would have money and so it's like well I
can spend 2,000 now because I'll look
out all this money I'll have in the
future I can pay it off with whereas
when that flipped when I knew I don't
know if I'm ever gonna be able to work
for a paycheck again I don't know if
that's ever gonna happen all of a sudden
all the money I had like my savings is
my savings I was like no and money kept
finding me like I got this very minor
traffic accident all I wanted was
chiropractic help that's all I wanted
but they ended up sending me like twenty
five hundred in compensation after all
of that now it was like it was very
minor I really only wanted chiropractic
but I was like oh and then I got like
all these tax returns that that's the
one it's the one thing that the ministry
doesn't take off of your money and so I
was like and then when you are on
disability and you apply for CPP you get
this lump sum of money and they don't
treat and so it's like this money founds
me you know it's like weird when I was
seeking it it ran away and now that I'm
like run away I don't need you and
actually fed on to me it's like I don't
know i-i've just in like I get all of
the abundance I need from society in a
very real way that usually isn't money
it's usually people offering things for
free and I that is what it's mine like
what if something costs a lot of money
and I can't afford it usual thing as all
you'll find the money if you meant for
you I'm like you know so how it'll work
out if it was meant for me I'll ask for
it for free right and sometimes that
doesn't make sense
cuz it's somebody's time and energy and
sometimes it does because it's a
technology thing or it's something that
people are willing to give up
and I got a long time ago for both my
health and wells unless it's free and
easy it's not meant for me or like super
cheap comes with a money-back guarantee
especially for my health because
everything's like zinc will change your
life
iron will change your life it all comes
down to iodine it's like great offer
money-back guarantee do you stand behind
that yeah so yeah and then my technique
my I entered this although my whole life
is leading up to this point like my
childhood my university my brain tumors
all of it I entered after mattli when I
knew I couldn't go back and do that work
with being a parent and them having
their rules and me I and I couldn't go
and learn something else I was like well
there's social enterprise there's
something here I can do and so I went to
school the school called groundswell
which was like a business school meets
hippies it was amazing
hilarious cuz nobody has a bit like a
handful they've had maybe I think six or
seven cohorts now and very few people
have a business out of it and at the
same time it's like life-changing it was
where I kind of figured out I was gender
queer and queerer and like all of this
other stuff I'm like but not a business
but every weekend I would go and come
back and be like I think I smoked to
join I pivoted and yet if I look at
everything I did during that time period
it was very related to what I'm doing
now it was all of it was nearly
everything was technology and it was
like well why can't this technology
exist in the world and it's kind of
dealing with the underlying structure of
the technology it's like that that it's
risky to create technology well I don't
want to take on that risk I want the
world to have this product I don't want
it to have this product it doesn't want
it like I wanted and so it's like okay
well if marketing and Finance has to be
dealt with with everyone and somehow
between the disability and not being
able to work and being at home with my
thoughts and going to this business
school and doing all of this it was like
a technology cooperative that we all own
and operate together with complete
transparency is the solution to
everything it's like because it's it
gives you the infrastructure you need to
have a personal autonomy to not give
it's like the best and this is my my
language alone before I discovered game
B it was like how we dismantle cap
is by creating a parallel system of
cooperation next to it that easily
outcompetes it with the vulnerable
transparency are talking about right
that like trust what exists right now in
the world only exists because of because
of a lack of information because we're
disconnected and we don't have all of
the information we don't trust the
information we do have if we have access
to information we can trust and use and
we're connected with one another in a
way that empowers us as individuals not
one big 7.5 billion kumbaya circle
because that's never gonna happen but
like how do I find my people and how do
I help you find your people and how do
we help each person live to their best
capacity in their own then we get all of
the stuff that comes out of that and the
more that we force it and the more that
we try to control it the harder it is
and it's funny because I'm a very I am a
controlling person I'm autistic and I'm
like I need things to be a certain way
like oh boy what's on the spectrum as
well probably yeah it's like the more I
know that I'd let go of it the more I'm
like okay I'm on it again if I strap
myself into the roller coaster I'm just
gonna instead of arguing that we're
going up and down no this is not okay
right now but it's like I still know the
controlling part of me and I can still
like in a conversation or in like it's I
used to love debates
I don't like debates anymore they're not
as funny because I'm like you win or you
lose they're not generative they're not
now I'm like I want generative
conversations and so over between that
conversation and that's three minute
video of a sorry video that I did in
September that I watched today and now I
think I must've been right after that I
launched the idea cafe which was like an
hour-long conversation on its its own
YouTube channel the idea was that it was
going to be formatted off from the World
Cafe everyone takes a turn answering the
question and you switch tables so that
you're having a bigger conversation with
the whole but it never really gained
traction like people like people love
participating in them but not
necessarily watching them so it doesn't
work in a game a world to gain an
audience and and I didn't follow through
that in the same way I did I was
reaching out to influencers and we it
was like my dashboard for what would be
my social media but I lost interest cuz
I found game B and I'm like there's all
these other cool things going on and
created game B in my head in my bedroom
all by myself before I ever knew what
game B was no and then even before I
found game B I knew that was broken I
was like oh if I create it even if it's
perfect I have to sell it to you I have
to explain it to you and you can't get
it all so what we need is we need to
create it together and I have enough
faith in what my brain created that's
actually what we naturally go to when
there's transparency and openness so we
can write it together mm-hmm and so the
idea Cafe and then I tried to do this
thing with with like it kind of with
extinction or buying kind of a game B
where I was like okay we're all in these
all different time zones we can have a
citizen's assembly every four to six
hours where because I have occupy
written down here and talked about 2009
2010 and occupy was one of my waking own
so it's like I love these mediums and oh
my god they take forever and nothing
comes out of them he's like you know
that how the meeting have a conversation
and not have everyone have their say how
everyone have their say but not have it
take up time and it's like the World
Cafe is that where it's like everyone
can have a conversation yet there's a
bigger conversation going on mm-hmm so
design it in this way which it never
really came to fruition so I don't know
if it would actually work but having
people come to a zoom meeting breaking
up into small groups and have it happen
every four to six hours right and so for
couple days you're answering the same
question then you have people harvest
that question to say I Principate all
these conversations here's what I
learned and not everyone has to harvest
it only people who want to harvest it
and finding a way to collect that
information but it was hard to get
people at the meetings
I can't facilitate every in every time
zone right so even every six hours I
can't do one every for every six hours
and so it when it coming out of that was
finding Bentley who we started together
tech was already the name I had going
but like a technology cooperative and my
brother came on board long after after
we did mushrooms my 40th birthday yeah
he's starting to see a bit of the vision
I've been talking about for years and
years he still has his own very
capitalistic spin on it but like he's
more into it now than he understands
game B but to be able to say okay here
is the technology cooperative at the
same time were very project
guest so out of that is 100 and nowhen
october/november Bentley had the idea
for a project raising where we praise
someone comes with their project and
they're in the hot seat and we focus on
their project they give the intentions
and we crowdsource it make perfect that
sounds great and they were great but it
was much easier finding people who
wanted a project raising then who wanted
to participate in somebody else's
project right right was basically a
troll Bentley and I appreciate
everybody's project but like yes fine
but like we want the meta project we
raised like how do we on the win
solutions for all of our projects and
somewhere in that we Alya was like from
Bentley newest project raising I was
like Oh a solution raising we can do and
so designing that hour-long conversation
in like here's what currently happens
here's what could happen in the
beautiful future of mine even if you
don't agree with it right they don't
need to match and then like what could
we actually do at ten thousand people
$100,000 because I know that when people
see that vision then it's like wait why
are we doing this exactly like once we
have the one for education and
infectious disease and transportation
and a few of these things it's like any
of these of the world changing imagine
if we had all of them right and they're
not it's not a brand new education
system it's like what could we do right
now that would improve education for my
kid or for me right and and then it's
like okay so now I am about how do I
find 10,000 be one less interesting I'm
more interested in finding us longer
than people to work through a process
and what could is a contest a something
looked like but 10,000 people they the
10,000 people got what they wanted out
of it they felt connected they felt like
they were part of it at whatever level
they wanted to be part of it yes and and
allowing that process to be done
transparently and openly including like
oh that didn't work that's falling apart
that's not quite working because the
more transparent you are the more
honestly put like space you have to make
mistakes because it's all of our mistake
like you also could have foreseen this
and helped with it you didn't right we
spent too much money well you could have
told us that this was actually on sale
for 75% off somewhere else you can't
come hindsight and tell us I already
spent that money right but we it's a lot
easier then go back and be like
look here's what we spent it on we had
too much when you knew $10 from everyone
right and if you're not willing to do
that that's fine like of course that's
okay it was our beginning like it's just
transparency makes everything better and
animate so I made some notes because I
did look through the stuff from the what
the one you sent me gonk oh come go go
go got that yeah thank you
yeah and a few of the other ones and one
of which is anyway would you like to go
through those sure yeah so during one of
the sections on one of the things it
talks about this this normal same that I
think is rather common in in socialism
communism right from each according to
their ability to each according to their
needs which is not it was like a slight
difference which is for each according
to their ability to each according to
their ability to serve the greater whole
and I like that because it does say like
like if I'm getting someone to clean my
house it's not because I'm better than
everyone else it's because I'm you seem
in energy to help serve the greater good
right and person cleaning my house is
using their energy to help serve the
greater good like it's it's it's in that
instead of I'm richer so I get it at the
same time there's a lot of ways that we
have no idea how somebody contributes
right all of the parenting which
generally falls on the women and they
don't have enough other to give it's
like right so and although like
secondary and tertiary giving right like
if you write a song and that inspires me
and then I go out and create the next
Facebook am i giving any money to the to
the writer you don't I mean like there's
ways that we're connected and inspired
and contribute that never really go back
to it to a currency to uh yeah Tolkien
yet right how does it end and beyond
that there's a lot of bias that comes in
in who we give credit to who we think
helps and who actually helped like the
person who takes the most right I did
all the good like I have this that most
people do but I'm we have people saying
that we're already
of course right yeah yeah but we're like
oh we have there's over estimators and
under estimators like the Trump is the
epitome of an over estimator right he's
the best at everything believe me and
the issue isn't that there's over an
under estimators it's that we kind of
assume everybody is an over estimator so
when you get somebody like me that's an
underestimate err you like you already
mean divide but what I've said by 75
instead of timesing it by 10 right so
when I say I know a solution to the
world and I'm coming as an underestimate
err you better believe me in a different
way than you should believe Trump but
you're never gonna know that and under
estimators like historically give more
because we think less of ourselves right
oh I can't cook so you put on 20 course
meal it's like a gourmet right and
you're like I can't do this so you do it
much more I you know my sister who is an
overestimate her for sure her one place
she was maybe an estimator which he
applied for film school
and didn't get in and so she did her own
small video and like won awards and
Australia and stuff because she didn't
know how shitty she was supposed to be
on it as a first year right like should
be it was like wait a minute
oh it just never appears to compare
herself to so it was above and beyond
what they would have done and I know
that happens in my life like when I cook
for people or when I throw a party or
when I do things because I think I'm so
bad at it then I overcompensate it ends
up being beyond I love that analysis
yeah but yeah totally so one of the
things I guess isn't crystal clear in
any of the stuff you read is the fact
this is all based on the meta currency
project which which was exactly that it
was exactly the idea that we're trying
to do to represent all of the value flow
all the things people value in the world
all the contributions that people are
making in the world through one metric
called money and if that fundamentally
just not going to work and of course you
know because the other part of that is
game a aspect that we're trying to get
more and more and more of it all the
time and the whole system but which is
created so the meta currency project
says that of each individual in each
community has the ability to recognize
the things that they value and to create
a currency around the things they value
that we can create
the kind of records we need to do proper
analysis on all of the things in the
world not just the things that can
funnel through money you know and that
definitely includes like one of the
primary examples I always use is whose
track whose where's the metrics for the
people raising the children I have three
girls I raised but then you know if I
can't show up in the way I need to do
business projects or something like that
because I'm raising my kids nobody cares
they're just like oh well you didn't
show up it doesn't matter that it
because I'm a dad I have three kids half
the year um so yeah I mean I've been
totally feeling that as well and which
but there's all kinds of different ways
of providing value in the world that
don't necessarily relate directly to a
monetary transaction unless we have the
capacity to start bringing bringing
awareness to those things that are
happening we're not gonna be able to
scale collectively intelligently but we
need to and so that is certainly a major
component I love the overestimate or
underestimate or thing you know analysis
I think one time I read that it's just
Western culture we are vastly
overestimated we are very immodest in
our capacities and in in Eastern
cultures they are much more modest they
are much more less think think less of
themselves and more of the collective
and he is also a masculine trait to
overestimate even though I don't really
like masculine feminine because it is
kind of that category of like all these
other categories we've decided to put
into a dichotomy which is like their own
dichotomy but that's all leather I end
up using it quite a bit the masculine
feminine dichotomy stuff um I think it
is it seems very prevalent to me and so
many things and I think it really is a
fundamental right so I end up using it a
lot and because it does throw people
sometimes for sure because I could say
Yin or yang because well a lot of times
people if I'm saying masculine or
feminine they think I mean male or
female they think I'm talking about
gender and Ike throws me off sometimes I
never am you know if you if you happen
to be in a female body and you're a
total masculine embodiment then that's
great mm-hm makes no difference to me
I'm gonna make friends it's to anybody
but it
is like it is it's very there's there's
things we can see in the approaches to
where you need that balance obviously
you need the masculine going out and
trying things out of cocky arrogance but
yet it's some kind of discovery process
right ya know and it's it's not you do
we need the diversity in the balance and
everything yeah and we don't have it
like right now under this Cove at 19
we're seeing how in order to start a
business you have to be an overestimate
er for sure and you have to have a high
risk tolerance and oh my god micro no
scene and it just kicked in in a way it
normally doesn't but that's double
weather like it kid like my micro nosy
and stuff I'll write you later oh no I'm
saying online but anyway I use less to
you that I normally do it was just like
usually it does it there isn't a kick in
moment and that moment I'm like wait
let's go that's what's going on you just
start yawning first that's the first
signs no no no um the balance the
whatever that may be lose my train of
thought which clearly means it's meant
to be
little little out-of-body at the moment
it's fun
rusty girl is it but when I was sitting
in fixing game a can be in my own
bedroom before encountering Danby
because one of the things that we say in
the world is that like we all have it
the unequal amount of hours in a day
right we have 24 hours in a day and that
it's fundamentally not true yes we have
24 hours in a day that's how long it
takes for the world to rotate but some
of us need more or less hours of sleep
some of us have chosen it you know what
I mean who needs child care like we have
different personal needs and we have
different societal needs that bring that
down so that we all have very
fundamentally very different amounts of
time we have very much different energy
we treat us like we have the same amount
of energy we think everyone should be
able to work a 40-hour workweek if
you're not able to you're a disabled if
you can work more than that you just get
all that surplus right there's people
who work 80 hours a week no problem on
marathons I don't think they're really
working 80 hours a week but that's
enough for me
anytime you tokenize them anytime you
add a currency to it you're gonna have
wrong incentives then it becomes then
you have this game theory and it's
finally agreed
your article on medium or you talked
about the computer it's game theory
right it's like if you if you're if
you're playing and a dichotomous game
and you can either you know do good or
bad and all of those are always done if
you both do good you're okay if one of
you does bad and one of you does good
the bad player gets the winning and then
if you both do bad either you get it it
plays on all the time in game theory and
I'm like why don't we ever and we
actually do sometimes but that's game a
right we incentivize sociopath we
incentivize bad actors but those games
are never done in a way that's like
right actually a game B can incentivize
the good winners the players and then
you actually don't need to play out game
theory because it's it's already in the
system right if when you when you have
bad and good actors and the good actors
win it doesn't actually matter what
about actors do right right the
sociopaths win right it's that when
you're willing to cheat when you're
willing to lie gives you an advantage in
the game right as opposed to we there is
no cheating and there is no lying
because we can fully see what
transparency what you're doing then it's
the good actor is it takeover and
therefore it doesn't matter whether
you're someone who like cuz this is the
idea that if you could work 80 hours a
week and you're choosing to only work
ten you're being lazy and you should be
penalized for that the issue is who that
actually penalizes are all the people
who actually can only work ten hours a
week right who like how do I prove I can
only work ten hours a week I don't know
I don't even gotta prove that's myself
well into the world right what is the
point so my metric instead of having a
currency I know follow chain and a
theory even savart go in and change
their ways but is that it's not about
the energy you put it and it's not about
the hours you put in it's literally
about what moment does it stop bringing
joy to you if you stop feeling joy your
tenth hour stop working if you stop it
at 80 hours stop working that it's not
about what anyone else is doing how much
work do you want to put into this
without worrying about what anyone else
is doing and that's the only thing
that's actually fair because whether
you're fully able-bodied or not the joy
is the difference right yes I would love
to put in 40 hours a week making
together Tec I can't but I but yet I do
hundred percent of me 24/7 is doing
together tech and at the same time the
actual putting the spreadsheets doing
that is a much smaller smaller amount of
time I guess yes just your thoughts on
that like having a token and the
incentivization in it well first of all
nothing in holo chain it talks about
tokens it's all current sees which is
fundamentally different in that while
we're trying to do is look at what's
actually happening and see the current
in those flows of exchange currency see
the current and so yeah there is this
element of tokenization for sure where
you've got to take something very
natural you have to do this extra step
where you have to put a metric on it and
then record that metric vulnerable
transparency does indeed take extra work
mm-hmm
and it's always a choice and so that is
an interesting you know challenge with
the whole thing for sure right but I
think that if if we kind of do get to a
point where there is a lot of vulnerable
transparency happening it should be
again like the people choosing not to do
it that would probably stick out say Oh
what not in there I'd like the guy you
have an interesting conversation with
Matt shooty who's one of the original
Medicare NC team who you know I'm four
I'm just 100% for vulnerable
transparency he's like you know I don't
know there's chameleons in nature
chameleons exist you know there's
there's certain need for certain things
to be kept closer to that I said okay
great that's true
we are following by a mimicking
biomimicry if we were working with
biomimicry and we are mimicking natural
patterns then yes there can be be so
that so this allows for that though so
my answer eventually was after thinking
about that for a while was yeah there
can be you can choose not to be
transparent but there's some evidence of
the existence view and/or your work so
we will see that you exist just like we
can catch a chameleon out of the corner
of your eye let's just saw something
over there I'm gonna when I look right
at it I can't see it but I know
something was there so now you're gonna
expect closer because you know something
seems to be hidden over there so now
you're actually gonna inspect look so if
you want to try not vulnerable
transparency I suspect the natural
pattern roll you will have more people
looking at you
mm-hmm and it won't work even with
honorable transparency and a baby I
don't like I'm not 100% sure on the
protocol that it is I didn't look
through it and I understood a bit of
what what is shown and what isn't shown
but if I'm an a player in this game and
I'm putting in the time I'm working it
I'm working on it what you're not seeing
is everything else I had to do to do
that right so for me my self-care might
take more than somebody else so somebody
else is able to put 40 hours of work in
and I'm only able to put 10 hours
working aside but 30 hours of South
Koreans put in that 10 hours right or
I'm a gopher estimator and I
overestimate that I put 10 hours in when
I actually put in to where someone else
is the under estimator and they
underestimate what they put in right
because even if I'm physically on my
computer for an hour and they're in a
computer for an hour that's not
productive hours one approach to metrics
certainly dry hours who do you think
that's the thing I mean my personal
perspective isn't collective that
actually consults with is more about
accountability so put a value on the
accountability at the Academy so you
have a factor of the difficulty and
experience level necessary and an time
difficulty experience time you factor
those together and then you would
perform the accountability or a few
people performance accountability and
then they have a rating after I mean
this is just one example of anything
that can be done with a transparent
ecosystem of exchange so and then when
it's done there's a rating you actually
have the feedback mechanism is always
the key it doesn't matter how much you
do right this is that was the point of
the adjustment and Marx quote it really
doesn't matter how much work you
supposedly do it matters whether you're
impacting life in a positive way or not
and the only way you know if you're
impacting life in a positive way is to
look for feedback mechanisms and to the
feedback myths and mechanisms are the
critical piece and so and what is
helping life in a positive way even that
you can't define the second we try to
were China we're telling people how they
have to ask the act in your social score
or else you don't get to fly on planes
or whatever because you didn't because
you went outside with the runny nose or
whatever it is so so punitive central
determination of what is good acting and
what is not is a
is just as problematic so if you
remember in there you might have read
somewhere in the document I don't maybe
didn't but I do have something called an
impact currency there's there's four
categories of exchange flows that
identify being critical one of them is
impact and that is the ability for
anybody to recognize what you or a group
of people a collective is doing and
assign an impact currency to them so the
common example is you have the the
factory who's making widgets that the
whole world loves and the world is a
better place because of the widget so
everybody loves the widgets but it's
polluting the stream and the people
downstream or it's not the widths are
not better for them in the in the net
right so they have the ability to create
an impact currency on that collective
and start coming up and they come up
with a metric of them out of sludge
that's going into the creek or whatever
and they can just assign that metric now
if they're the only ones in the world
who care about that it won't mean much
that's a fact but it will be there and
as more and more people start to
identify hey what lay I'm gonna look at
the impact currency oh look at this
negative six million four hundred
billion or whatever that they have that
they've that their account is holding
from this community somebody can look at
that and if that becomes important and
that catches on that becomes an
important metric that people want to pay
attention to now it means something yeah
right so it's all interpersonal meaning
we don't get no one person or no one
central bodies should in my opinion
determine what is impactful and what is
good for life every actor in the system
gets to play and then of course we need
we need the people who will speak for
the trees and speak for the creeks and
speak for the mountains and speak for
the birds and you know the Lorax we need
all the Lorax among us to also
participate and there's probably a role
just for them and doing that in doing
the best and of course the science can
be involved actual data collection on
things that aren't human experience
related feedback mechanisms we can have
data collection mechanisms you know
people who are play those roles and so
the what I would also say is that
everything all the contributions you're
making all of the all of the things you
just there isn't there isn't a type of
value
that gets recorded in a type that
doesn't anything you want to record
should be recorded that means if you
want to record you know how you're
performing some kind of accountability
for the world or or whatever it for 24
hours a day that includes raising your
children that includes being mom that
includes all the things you have to do
and and that's that's what's encouraged
I mean that's that's more vulnerable
transparent than not doing it right so
yeah the issue is a lot of that stuff
can't actually I can tell you what I'm
doing for 24 hours
it doesn't look productive right I'm
spending quality time with my kid for an
hour oh wait what are you doing together
23 hours right well I'm sleeping for 12
of those hours I'm you know down time
watching television because my brain
can't you know like there's a lot that
looks like unproductive time and it is
unproductive time but it allows me to
have the productive time right other
people and that ratio is completely
different right they can rotate week I
can't assign hours very common in game a
is the judgment about what we you know
you just lose that we can lose the
judgment we all know that we're all just
doing what we can yeah and that's who we
are
and of course basic needs do need to be
met ultimately anything that's gonna
anyway we're gonna be able to shift into
this is gonna support people in their
basic needs no matter what like you hear
you play and that's what we try to do
through programs like welfare but
there's very much a social judgement
about all that so you're on welfare so
now you're not a productive like lose
all that because it's it's you
know it's just it's just okay
you have to try really hard to not be
giving anything to the world actually
like what if you choose to smoke pot and
sit around play video games all day I'm
like I'm literally smoking pot and
playing video games or watching TV all
day and I figure out how to save the
world
so you can't really discount that like
you really you're having conversations
you're part of the world you're still
buying things you're still eating you're
still contributing and you're still
taking and giving you're part of it
thank you Doug and even the bad actor is
even people who I look at who I wish
once in my life right I'm like oh that
interaction wasn't bad it's what I've
learned the most from
there there I'm like you're actually
working out perfectly
exactly and meant to be and coming into
contact so yeah have you um are you
familiar with Ramsey's project common
planet in their currency system no but
there's so many yeah I'm I'm I do know
somebody named Ramsey I'm not sure if
it's the same one he gave me I don't
know if there's more than one runs the
endgame be thanked and common planning
he's the one who actually introduced me
to gain B I found him we put each other
on Twitter and we talked like a year in
a bit ago and then he interested you can
be in September but I really like their
currency there they came up with it for
like a resource-based economy but not
they can actually get to a
resource-based economy so the basic
understand gets a universal basic income
just for existing but how currency is
generated is by working and then it's
spent and it goes into the ether it
doesn't circulate so if I if I think my
neighbor needs their house cleaned and
offer that to them and I go and clean
their house for them I'm getting paid to
clean their house that they're not
paying me right it's like I can choose
where my Labor's most needed
meaning it's probably going to be in the
currencies generated in that way I have
a whole other issues I'm like awake then
why would I ever clean my house my
neighbor cleans my house and I clean
their house and we generate an income
perfect and other other things like that
but I like I like that idea for currency
if there's gonna be a currency for
together tech my vision not necessarily
our vision is that you first look for
the incentives that are internal that
don't need to be paid and then when
things aren't done under that under that
umbrella then you start looking for its
turtle incentives and so because I have
this three circle Venn diagram it's
always around me somewhere because I've
written it out so many times it's like
for anything to get down in our economy
you need one person to have the skill to
do the tasks to be aware of the task
needs to get down and to want to do the
task and there's a way to compensate for
all of that our current economy is only
about compensating for people who don't
want to do the tasks and we just pay and
you've never actually got the internal
incentivization Wow
you can create a system of information
so people who are trained and wants to
do the task know the task needs to get
done and in education systems you can
train people who want to do the task and
are aware of it but just don't know how
then that other piece figures itself out
mostly and the things that don't need to
get done if it's just glaringly obvious
they're not done right like potholes
aren't filled and you just know potholes
aren't filled then we keep asking what
would get us to fill the potholes right
is it that there aren't enough people
trained do people not want to okay what
what if there was music what if it was a
fun festival to fill the potholes like
what would get us to actually do it
that's not just about great can we pay
you 25 bucks an hour to fill them yeah
yeah please but right god so many
threads here I'm unfortunately out of
time it's like what a quick out were
just getting started yeah
yeah I don't know do you want to try
tomorrow at the same time but by any
chance er try to think what tomorrow
tomorrow's Tuesday I did it on Monday
for a reason cuz Tuesdays and Wednesdays
are already pretty busy but Thursday do
you have time on Thursday it's a no this
time I'm always good generally all right
yeah let's do Thursday at 7:00 again
yeah cuz I've got to go i have my 8:30
in 15 minutes i have my usual live on my
channel correct myself for an hour so
it's fun and then if anyone chimed said
in joins and then other i have kids
stuff to do later like my kids teacher
and the principal and I are meeting
later today but yeah beautiful and then
Thursday's aren't very full cool yeah
yeah well good um there's some so many
threads we could follow right there so I
really look forward to I've so much I
wanted to say and so I'll do that
Thursday thank you so try to keep my
notes also one of the last things I
wanted was like your your version of
transparency so if I don't remember it
like that because I love the idea of
opting into transparency and there are
also organizations that I'm not willing
to let them opt-in to transparency like
government existing corporations I'm
like nope we're going to be transparent
for you we're gonna write and we expect
a politician to opt in to transparent
it's like you opted into it when you
joined politics like that was you opting
in and we can we can record right if the
informations there it just isn't
organized and we can organize it so that
that is them opt into it in a way but I
don't want your thoughts on yeah great
one and you know the short answer is the
moment we start judging the other
because they're less transparent and
remote we're getting into rivalry
so we're saying now I'm rivals with you
because you're not transparent enough
we're right back to game a right so it's
like it's a parody yeah so let's get
into that conversation because that is
I'm like but they're already in gaming
this isn't like game B after asking how
transparent you want to be this is like
sugar throwing into the ocean and
being like people don't know about it
yeah I guess my grip my idealistic
theory is that all we have to do is
invent a new oil company that doesn't
that operates completely vulnerable
transparency everybody will come to us
and leave them because the world's ready
I'm just gonna stop recording yes